publicdomainreview.org 2019-12-25

# Privacy Policy – The Public Domain Review

The Public Domain Review is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy and we have taken measures to be [GDPR](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/) compliant. We know your privacy is important to you and will only use your personal information to provide the products and services you have requested.

This Policy explains when and why we collect personal information from visitors to our website, how we use it, the conditions under which we may disclose it to others and how we keep it secure.

We may change this Policy from time to time so please check this page occasionally to ensure that you’re happy with any changes. By using our website, you’re agreeing to be bound by this Policy.

Any questions regarding this Policy and our privacy practices should be sent by email to [enquiries@publicdomainreview.org](mailto:enquiries@publicdomainreview.org), or by writing to The Public Domain Review, 87 South Drive, Manchester, M21 8ED, United Kingdom.

### Who we are

The Public Domain Review is an online journal and not-for-profit project dedicated to the exploration of curious and compelling works from the history of art, literature, and ideas. We are registered as a Community Interest Company in the United Kingdom (#11386184). Our website is publicdomainreview.org.

### How and when we collect information

There are broadly two kinds of information we collect:

a) “personal” information, which you actively provide to us through forms on our site;

  * **Newsletter sign up:** name and email address.
  * **Buying something from the shop or making a donation (via PayPal account):** name, email address, postal address, billing address.
  * **Buying something from the shop or making a donation (via debit/credit card):** name, email address, postal address, billing address, debit/credit card details (encrypted via Stripe or PayPal, not seen or held by us).

b) “non-personal” information which is passively provided to us — anonymous tracking data for the purpose of analytics and for the basic functioning of certain aspects of the site such as the cart and checkout for our shop.

  * **Cookies:** Like many other websites, The Public Domain Review uses cookies. Cookies are small text files placed on your computer to collect standard internet log information and visitor behaviour information. This information is used to track visitor use of the website and to compile statistical reports on website activity — they do not identify you as an individual. For further information visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/)g or [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)g. You can set your browser not to accept cookies and the above websites tell you how to remove cookies from your browser. However, please be aware that some key aspects of our website features may not function as a result.
  * **Google Analytics:** We use Google Analytics to collect and process basic information about your visit to help us improve our service. This usage of Google Analytics is minimal and anonymous (we have a tool to anonymize your IP address). We do not make use of their advanced features such as those used in advertising which identify you as an individual.

### What we do with your information

We are committed to protecting your privacy. Under no circumstances do we rent, trade or share your e-mail address with any other company for their marketing purposes.

The personal information that you provide is used solely in fulfilment of the specific service requested. For example, the name and email address you provide when signing up for the newsletter will only be used for the purpose of sending you the newsletter; the information you provide when placing an order is used only to process and fulfil your order. This necessarily involves sharing certain details with other companies who we partner with (such as fulfilment or delivery companies in the case of placing an order, or the mailing application Sendy in the case of sending out the newsletter). While we cannot take responsibility for the privacy policies or practices of these partner companies, they have all been carefully chosen because they too promise to take your privacy seriously and assure to keep your data safe. We also use your personal information for our own internal purposes, such as providing customer support or providing, maintaining, evaluating and improving our products and services.

We partner with credit card processing companies (Stripe and PayPal) to assist us in processing any payment made on the site. However, those companies do not retain, share, store, or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes. You may see the privacy policy of Stripe [here](https://stripe.com/gb/privacy), and Paypal [here](https://www.paypal.com/en/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full).

We retain the right to pass on the personal and non-personal information of our customers to any successor-in-interest of ours, such as a company that acquires our business, but only if such a business complies with GDPR law and similar terms as set out in this privacy policy.

We may need to disclose your personal information when required by law or when we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process.

### Your choice to opt-out of certain communication

If you are signed up to our Newsletter and no longer wish to receive e-mails from us then please follow the unsubscribe instruction in our e-mails or e-mail your request to [enquiries@publicdomainreview.org](mailto:enquiries@publicdomainreview.org). Note that you may still receive vital customer service related communications from us, if relating to our duties in filling out any future order you might make. What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. Please email: [enquiries@publicdomainreview.org](mailto:enquiries@publicdomainreview.org).

### Protecting your data

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information such as a credit card number on our order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). All our pages are protected by SSL technology. We only gather the minimum data necessary, and only retain it for as long as is necessary.

### Amazon Affiliates

The Public Domain Review is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to Amazon. Certain links on our site will point to Amazon with a URL which is appended by our unique referral code. This referral code will indicate to Amazon that you have arrived to their site from our site, and so items bought on that particular visit may earn us a small referral fee (depending on which items you purchase).

### Changes to our Privacy Policy

If we change our Privacy Policy, we will post a new version on our Website, which will become effective when posted. The new policy will apply to all current and past users of the Website and will replace any prior policies that are inconsistent with it.

### Contact us

If you have any questions regarding our privacy policy please contact [enquiries@publicdomainreview.org](mailto:enquiries@publicdomainreview.org).
